why aren't you guarding its 256 I've
rolled over to zero and so I thought it
would just be silence right I mean it's
it's it's an 8-bit integer so now it's
256 so therefore it's zero and then
that's just silence why don't we just
not really it's an episode because then
how are we ever gonna get to 257 that
doesn't fit in eight bits there's a lot
of problems with this logic well there
was that a release episode zero but we
never made an episode zero we foolishly
started with one all right if you were
still listening welcome to our bedded as
you can tell this is gonna be a little
bit of a silly show where we answer a
listener questions and talk about how
you can be a rockstar programmer okay
okay and since it is episode 256 at the
first order of business his lightning
round now is the cupcakes you got
cupcakes right I have this plan where I
just mash them in my mouth Cookie
Monster style and the the sprinkles and
the the confetti cake goes everywhere
until my microphone is encrusted in
frosting and sugar and that's how I'll
always be I think we're gonna do that
there's some astronaut ice cream on a
desk but that's all I don't have any
cupcakes this is not a good start
we could go out for cupcakes after the
show and then cut in the portion of us
sounding like Cookie Monster yeah I I
don't think that's gonna work that's
just you're saying you don't want
cupcakes we don't need to record the
cupcakes I'm not I'm never saying it
they record the cupcakes it'll sound a
lot like the first minute of the show
with chewing sounds okay let's uh yes
hi welcome to the show what a show is
this this is show 256 this isn't bad
labor the parts I didn't better you did
I have introduced you your your Chris
Chris white and I'm Elysia white and we
do this show about engineering and
cupcakes about what it's about
sometimes let's see first I have random
news to get out of the way first of the
news bits is that we have a newsletter
in case news about news you prefer email
as the way to get information about the
show and blog
apparently RSS is dead I keep hearing
this but the newsletter is basically
just RSS and email next next I'm sure
that now having started the show that
now is when you say you know what I wish
I could support these people in the
effort they put into this show if you
feel that way you are welcome to support
us on patreon which is this little
program where you put in your credit
card and then every month they take out
a dollar or four or however many dollars
you tell them they can take out and in
return for that you get the satisfaction
of knowing that our guests have better
mics and that you buy us cupcakes which
and they can join our competitive him
slack group right that is true that is
part of the posts in the patreon and
things go on there
jobs are posted conversations happen and
sometimes we're out sometimes we're
around and sometimes we're not and
I have to say they're a very interesting
group of people for yeah about all kinds
of things and so it's a lot of people
now actually it's what it's over a
hundred club something like up yeah and
and people have offered electrical help
or software help or what chip should I
use in this yeah it's really cool
one other reason to support on patreon
is the idea that we might do transcripts
yeah yeah you can hear Christopher's
excitement about that
let me guess them but a couple of people
vast for various reasons and one of our
listeners has offered to try out doing
them and Thank You Fred and if it goes
well then we might do more pay for
professional services so far is just
going to do a couple to see if anybody
actually uses them so if you want to say
yes I would use them then go ahead and
let me know on email or just really want
to use them not oh that sounds like a
great idea but you know you have to
think deep in your head would I actually
use these not yeah because if fred is
doing it out of the goodness of his
heart and I don't want to to ask him to
do a bunch because he's a embedded
systems professional and has things to
do but I mean it it's pretty expensive
once we've got dollar a minute it's like
a dollar I don't it that's especially
since our material is technical so we
don't want we can't just do the auto
cheapest automated no right now Google
does automate it on YouTube that's
pretty pretty it is pretty bad every
every week I look to see exactly how the
intro is how they spelled my name or
what they did instead of my name I liked
the day we were I'm under the sea white
yeah that was nice but it would help
people like
Okarche who wanted us to put in time
stops and markers in the show notes so
chapters I can do chapters the one of
the programs i used to put the podcast
together supports inserting chapter
marks I've thought about it it requires
me to pay a different kind of attention
well while we're recording or while I'm
editing to actually generate topical
chapter marks because we often do random
yeah and I would rather have a good
conversation I didn't have topics if
people again if people really want this
we need to have some more volume of
requests because it is it is a pain in
the neck and I think if we did
transcripts then that would solve some
of his problems too sure because he
could his goal was to skip to the
something excited mentioned in the show
notes so if we had the transcripts he
could find that of course I don't know
where to put the transcripts but we'll
figure that out when it comes to it
we'll have to get our web point we have
one the website a website yeah yeah we
do have a website just like the
transcript in that episode thing do you
hear something
yeah I can't wants to join the show
she's like it's 256 it's time for me to
be on again but last I checked she drew
tired so I don't know what let's just
gonna talk about okay do you want to do
listener questions first or Rockstar
programming skills do like your listener
questions okay from Behati get a go who
enjoys our podcast has been tinkering
with the st micro f1 series that's one
of their low-end playing around with the
hal and the standard peripheral library
library is poorly documented mmm he said
it not me
or possibly and yeah anyway well I
should have read it out as as Behati
because I don't know it's it's not great
it
and how do you want to know what we use
for programming est macro bare metal or
micro libraries or what I don't use s T
so violate this to you um it depends on
which chip you have and what you're
doing with it I had a client recently
who was relatively an experienced client
wanted a demo system and wanted to be
able to modify things after I was not no
longer part of the project I put them on
embed which has an operating system it
has a Hal it has lots of nice fun things
it has a compiler and it is not
something I would do for high production
but it is a great place to start it's
it's more complicated than Arduino and
less complicated than any other option
for another client I recently used cube
which is estie's linked together all of
the i/o pins and set up your clocks and
it's all graphical and then it spits out
a bunch of code and it has all your
drivers written for you and you can even
set up DMA it's actually really great
for setting up da makes it makes it kind
of easy and straightforward but that's
not a replacement for how that generates
everything you need to do to call Hal so
it's it's actually a hardware
abstraction layer made graphical and
then setup according to how you want so
you decide how you want your chip
configure it your knots or a bunch of
questions and this graphical thing and
it spits out headers basically and some
code that sets up the chip the way you
want this configuration don't want these
GPIO is to go do this in this
configuration of what these clocks
configured this way and then it spits
all that out for you yeah that seems
very useful but that does that that
doesn't blow your code or anything it's
just right as he's how is not the most
efficient oh because Cube calls the
coz cube cause the hot gotcha and the
standard prefer a library which I mean
it's not bad but it does things like
every time you toggle a GPIO it checks
to see if the GPIO is valid
that's great sometimes but if you
actually want to go fast you have to
trust that your GPIO is valid and just
do the one clock cycle thing it also
because it does things like check to see
the GPIO is valid each time that is code
and it puts a lot of that code in a lot
of codes you don't need a lot of code
you maybe don't want and so yeah it
bloats your code and it slows your
processor it is very easy though if you
are running a cortex m0 with only a
little bit of flash space you probably
want to go straight bare-metal if you
are running a cortex m4 and it's twice
as big as you need
use cute makes it easy so yeah it
depends it was a long minute say it
depends well good yeah I kicked bringing
up cube is a a lot of people are
advocating for and against it some of
them the same people at the same time so
it's kind of hard to decide but it seems
like one of the things you could start
with and see what it does yes it is a
good place to start with because it
shows you what it's doing it doesn't
generate library code you can't read it
generates C codes you can read and even
the how things it calls into you can
read and then you can strip out what you
don't want and even from my kind of
osmotic experience with s T it seems
like some of those configuration things
are really challenging without something
like this like the clock setup but I've
seen diagrams so the clock tree is you
could put it on your wall and you know
it has 40 different nodes that you have
to figure out it's true and it does make
it easier to set up like I said I used a
cube recently for a professional project
because it was a little simpler it was
also simpler to explain
the client what I was doing although
later the client wanted to swap pins and
I was like should I tell him to do it
and cube should I just go ahead and use
the code and never regenerate or should
I just do this myself
I chose the latter that is the question
with auto-generated stuff is do you use
the auto generation graphical tool all
the time whenever you make a change or
do you use it to get your first cut of
setup code and then from then on
maintain in his code I mean his
arguments both ways but I would kind of
like cut and run how sure during the
initial setup and things were working
and if you had to make changes make him
in the code it's a choice because you
don't know and you should document what
you're doing because you don't want
someone woman later and then again right
and you might get a different version
right they might update it and then you
go in and auto-generated to make a small
change and suddenly everything's changed
and you've got this massive patch and
you're not even sure if it's changed
anything substantive right so you to be
careful with auto-generated code well
that's one reason that in Andrews blog
he he very specifically says don't put
any code in main like put like the one
line that calls your functions the there
should be an an it call an a loop call
and you just call those and nothing else
goes in main because you never know
what's gonna change or what's gonna be
killed
he's written a lot about this he really
has so if you want to know more about
cube NST and and what's in there check
out and raise embedded Wednesday plug
okay you highlighted the Hippocratic
oath for connected medical devices I
highlighted it so I could open it and
look at it and see what it was because
there was no description so we might as
well talk about now yes so you have a
link in here and it's a long URL I'm not
gonna repeat but I'll be in the show
notes but basically it's a document
called the Hippocratic oath for
connected medical devices where did this
come from
I am the Calvary org which is one of
those organizations that works to make
security and privacy more understandable
to both see
consumer and engineering communities
that you've come by I was looking around
for trying to explain to a potential
client that their plan for ble on their
medical device was not kosher which they
did eventually take that advice and
start to understand what the HIPAA
compliance would mean for them so the
traditional Hippocratic oath I don't
know if it's always laid out in its
complete form but it seems rather simple
and short I will do no harm and let's
look it up yeah but you've read this one
I'm assuming yes yes
so okay it's quite that it's actually
it's in ancient Greek so I can't I can't
read it well I don't know the alphabet
either so that that makes it a little
bit more difficult not to be confused
with hypocrisy by the way yes that's
important I swear by Apollo the healer
well that's an interesting start okay
well basically it's the core of it is
first you no harm so this is similar
idea this is a similar idea in taking
responsibility for the ethics of medical
devices particularly connected medical
devices
I will revere and protect human life and
always act for the benefit of my
patients I recognize that all systems
fail inherent defects and adverse
conditions are inevitable and it goes on
from there where it talks about how
failure impacts patient safety and how
we have to be resilient against
accidents and intentional adversaries
such as hackers
and it goes on to talk about cyber
safety in the design and and evidence
capture so that you can figure out when
something goes bad and I just I wanted
to bring this up as a people wonder well
what do I have to do what are my
responsibilities you don't have to take
this oath but you should at least look
at it it's rather long to take as an
oath stay allowed but it goes through
what all these things means about
working with third parties and shared
responsibilities and testing I just it's
a pretty long document that talks about
as an engineer yeah what should your
ethical responsibilities be towards the
people who maybe have your device
implanted in them I think the core of it
is the same first you no harm and then
they go on to describe in several ways
how to accomplish that yeah that's
that's excellent I wished I'd had that
many times at least at a minimum to show
to people yes this is even more
convincing than hey I don't look good in
orange right I'm not I'm really glad
somebody put this together it's actually
a few years old yes it is it's not new
and I bet someone had pointed to any
swearing to God's here which is an
oversight no Apollo here no no Apollo no
SLPs no hygeia no pen SIA panacea so I
think I think they need to add that take
okay what do you think the guards should
be for a technology related thing I mean
I don't want to swear to woz he's not
really a god what book am I thinking of
the head weird emergent cyber gods
half of them that have been reading oh
you know what I think was the Hyperion
series later that's an Hyperion series
there there were gods called Aloha or
something that lived in in their
equivalent of the universe wide Internet
yeah
Aloha are usually if who do you think
yeah that's what they were modeled after
okay anyway this is cool you should
check it out especially if you work on
medical devices any of you who don't
work on medical devices you know what
some of this applies to all kinds of
things if you're working on automotive
airplanes involve safety take a look at
this please see from Paul sort of in Li
related but not really make recently had
an article where they talked about how
to tighten security for do-it-yourself
IOT gadgets so please stop putting those
raspberry PI's unprotected with no
password on the raw Internet people do
that do beautifully people do that let's
just punch an IP hole in make scene make
magazine has top tips to tighten your
security so I will link to that it's
copyrighted but it might be worth a
discussion just going through all the
lists and talking about each I don't
think we're going to do that today
though cuz we have a lot to do and we
stuff to buy cupcakes all right where do
you want to talk about it I read it at
the time but I don't have any particular
memory of it I mean where we should be
breathe through it real quick and change
the default user password obvious but
yes purple eyes there are default user
passwords yes
I mean if it's raspberry or pie its
default disable password login with SSH
which you know we all use it for
debugging another one you might not be
aware is enabled yeah up to ear OS
because they don't just make the updates
for fun sometimes they do well sometimes
it you have a firewall yeah yeah I mean
these are motherhood and apple pie stuff
this was like the time that Chris and I
are having this long discussion and I
came down strongly in favor of reading
he pointed out to me that this was not
news and then they have some stuff for
all devices interestingly they say use a
VPN oh I see to get into your home stuff
that makes sense I would not recommend
necessarily using a VPN for your general
use there's a lot of those out there and
people make a big deal out of protecting
your security from the ISPs by using a
VPN for all of your surfing and whatnot
I have a mixed feelings about that
because you're just transferring your
trust to somebody else do you trust
random VPN company more than your ISP
maybe but it's at least a question you
should ask random VPN company has less
vested interest in controlling you yes
but you know nothing about them well
there is that
that that is that is a little nervous
making their entire business model could
be stealing your stuff and selling it
and they could be based in a country
you're not aware of something anyway
just know what you're doing but yeah
good stuff and it's worth it's worth at
least especially with the Linux based
ports like the Raspberry Pi or you might
not be aware of things that are open by
default or at least more open than you
want cool Tyler is a firmware engineer
working at a start-up in New York City
and it's thinking about starting to meet
up Tyler wants to attract other
engineers and people interested in
embedded systems to attend others
looking for people interested in joining
presenting something something yeah it
would have been good if I had replied to
Tyler and said ok do you have a plan but
at this point
Tyler has just said like let's do a
meet-up in New York City you put this
and enough I know if you would like to
speak at Tyler's event or you would like
to be connected with Tyler or something
yes
feel free to email me show at embedded
FM I do eventually read all of the
emails I don't reply to them all the
time are well organized yeah well there
are still some sticker offers that are
like six months old so I will eventually
get to you I promise I now we have a
bunch of C++ questions these are your
favorite ah yes
okay just listen to number 247 on C++
with Jason Turner and was thinking is
that an interesting question of whether
the language properties of C++ help the
compiler generate optimal code are also
helpful for the programmer to write and
understand and maintain in a complex
project well I guess we have to define
what the language properties of C++
which help the compiler generate optimal
code are those some of the things we
talked about with Jason some of the
iterators some of the libraries I think
that my answer is generally yes most of
those things are helpful to the
programmers that they aren't necessarily
helpful to C programmers who don't know
them because there's always a learning
curve but the whole idea behind C++ is
to generate more structured code write
gain objects the whole object-oriented
mindset whether or not you like it or
not the impetus behind it was to
structure your code in a more modular
fashion so I think to the extent that
those structural things help the
compiler I'm not sure that some of them
do that the answer is yes but smaller
details like the newer features like
iterators and such
they're more expressive and by
expressive I mean you're able to
accomplish more complicated things in
less code so it depends on how you feel
about expressive languages if you feel
that Express of languages help you
organize your code better and produce
better code then also yes but if you
feel like expressive languages are hard
to learn and complicated from a
syntactic standpoint because you have to
know all these weird idioms and ways of
doing things that maybe you could do and
see quite easily because the only how to
know a few key words then know you can
be a bad programmer in any language
right yes I think I think a lot of these
arguments about which language is better
and people get in their minds that don't
C++ is terrible or oh you should all be
using C sharp or you know Haskell's the
way to go or whatever you mistrust and
Erlang and go or we have to say those or
people will email the rest is bad Thanks
how did I just one more email I'd spend
people to don't love me if I say Russ is
bad I'll get email it doesn't have to be
good email no where was my point my
point was it's
there's nothing magical about any of
these things I feel I mean there's
nothing great about CEA's language
except it was it's very old it's very
easy to shoot your foot off but you know
there's there's good things about it and
there's bad things about it and if you
don't know what you're doing if you
aren't using the language kind of the
way it was intended then it's easy to
write terrible code and people tell me
oh I've heard people say all the time I
was he plus plus you it just makes
spaghetti code and my projects that I've
done C++ on you can make spaghetti code
in any language and I do think it's it's
you know it's all of our biases about
what we've seen in a particular language
and my bias against Trust has nothing to
do with rust have never used rusts since
its point it's stupid it's just named a
language after something awful okay yeah
rust maybe you know if I used rest I
might become an advocate for it so my my
my character persona playing a rust
adversaries it's just that I I tend to
think that more lines of code are harder
to maintain that's true but if they're
in a language you don't know then
they're impossible to maintain so if
you're going to have expressive
idiomatic C++ then you have to learn
that language you can't I mean wait if
you ever look at my Python code I write
C in Python it's it's not pretty I
occasionally manage to do a dictionary
slice that looks good but overall no not
so much and so and yet I can read the
Python that's pretty although once they
get multiple them doesn't one line I'm
kind of lost cuz I just yeah and I think
easily distract I think we can talk
about two different things right we can
talk about that syntactic we just don't
know the language
yeah don't know it with a facility to to
read it and it's easier to not know a
language that's more expressive
and it was those features of the
language the Jason was talking about as
far as optimizing it to be better so to
pull back from the yes a little bit in
principle you can generate cleaner nicer
code but it's harder to read for the
completely uninitiated fluent non-fluent
programmer and you know what the same
principles that make good code apply to
all languages right modularity
testability interfaces testability
keeping things small and tight using the
language to its best abilities Oh
sometimes I mean I have seen a sim I
have seen C I've seen assembly written
in C basically yeah I've seen C
programmers who don't really bother with
for loops who only know that the while
loop is a thing
there are ways in any language you can
make it look terrible and illegible and
the best you can do
oh well yeah let's just talk smack about
Perl you really want some emails don't
you are you lonely
yeah and C++ is not easy to learn no
it's not gonna not gonna deny that so
let's go on to the next C++ question
which Jason Turner stated that c-sharp
and Java have much big coders backs Kodi
code code specifications then C++ I
would put that down to my sugar crash
except Christopher didn't get cupcakes I
didn't know I was supposed to C sharp
and Java have much bigger code specs
than C++ but surely C++ and Java are
higher-level languages there thank you
guys I think at this point C++ is pretty
high level I mean this I guess they have
garbage collectors so they make them
higher level I think they have big
libraries of support stuff which makes
their specs better bigger does that make
them a higher-level language
I don't know agglomerating libraries
doesn't count as language to me
so glommer 80 yeah i glommer a ting
that's a words that aggregation and
conglomeration at the same time glommer
aiding agglomeration it's right here
it's word did you just add it to the
wiki dictionary no economies of
agglomeration anyway
it's perfectly common that word okay so
the answer here is I don't know yeah I
don't know I I think I tend to think of
C++ Java C sharp had around the same
level and the reason Java and c-sharp
have bigger specs is because they have
frameworks attached to them and C++ does
not count frameworks as part of a
language yeah if you added C++ and
OpenCV and C++ as a single spec then it
would be enormous yeah okay so this
question I believe we can answer today
on questions we won't and can't answer
but we will talk about rayon I am
currently taking a see a slash C++
programming class and my instructor
insists on us using not using
parenthesis unless they are absolutely
needed you banging the table yes
to paraphrase phrase the teachers line
of reasoning use of unnecessary of
parenthesis clutters the code and
advertises the programmers lack of
knowledge understanding or and
experience Ryan says I don't have a
problem with this it's his class so I
should play by his rules I tend to think
it's just a balancing act it's okay to
use quote unnecessary parens judiciously
especially if you think there's a good
chance your expression it could be
misread by others or the future you
after all
I doubt that the typical competent
professional programmer has memorized
the entire operator precedence chart so
ran your instincts are 100% correct in
every way and your professor whomever
they are
doesn't listen to that a professional
programmer and they have a weird sense
of aesthetics that has nothing to do
with clean code or maintainability
parentheses cost nothing and while it is
possible to use so many that makeup
becomes unreadable I think the
likelihood of that is far less than
using too few and getting into serious
problems because you screw up an
operator precedence or some weird
casting thing use them did you know
there's no przemek instruction being
generated if you run out of parentheses
I believe and Ray will strip your soul
ship you some from Canada artisanal
parentheses yes yeah I I was pretty sure
you'd answer I was shocked when I saw
this it's like who would argue for for
using the minimum parentheses necessary
why I you don't do that big man hands
you don't do that in men I'm for doing
reams of homework right in like physics
and math do you write parentheses on
stuff so you don't screw up III know I
know I know I'm I'm not yeah sorry I
anybody who wants to argue with the lack
of parentheses being better you can send
emails I mean it's one thing to say you
shouldn't wear socks with sandals and I
I actually want to know what happens if
your professor tries to teach Lisp I
believe his head will explode
it's a see us professor okay what did
the parentheses do to this person is
what I want to know yeah what's the
story there
what's the what's the backstory yes you
don't get disobey okay now now for the
the part you've all been waiting for
what the end of the show
like those Muppets do you want to talk
about the new Muppet movie no I don't
know anything about it what I've told
you rock star rock star programming
something that is often I termed as you
know kind of people put it on job wrecks
we want a rock star programmer or ninja
code ninja and then other people say why
don't we just have to have a developer
why don't we just have people who do
their jobs why do we have dad corns and
and do you really want to work with the
rock star the trash hotel rooms know
constantly drug drunk yeah um so but we
want to go beyond that on how you can be
a rock star programmer without trashing
the hotel room so this this guy Dylan BT
forgive me if I've mispronounced your
name
has proposed the Rockstar programming
language it is turing-complete and the
cool thing about it is it's like you
could actually do it and how it works is
all of your language keywords and such
go together to construct lyrics so yeah
so somebody so he's got an example of
his buzz in the most poetic
implementation you can you can be less
poetic well do you want to talk about
what fizzbuzz is and ruin all of the
interviews that are gonna happen next
week as buzz as they sit okay s word
gonna be fizzbuzz is a basic programming
interview question on the complexity
level of store copy or maybe a little
less oh no I think this buzz is a little
more right okay it's a very reasonable
often used programming you go through a
loop incrementing a value and if it's
modulo 3
I'm doing this from memory you print
fizz if it's modulo 5 you print buzz if
it's modulo both you do newline or put
in the cursors character to shake the
screen I don't know what does it do
it's supposed to print out something
like 1 to fizz for buzz fizz 7/8
fizzbuzz 11 fizz 1314 fizzes right okay
so it's both you didyou fizzes anyway so
yeah the simple little tip a little
problem so you can see you'd have for i
equals 0 for e and I equals 0 to
whatever and you'd have if give the
whole answer me you know if this is
modulo 3 then we print this if it's
modular private we print this and blah
blah and you can do some clever things
and and people look for the clever
things anyway in rockstar they give an
implementation that is basic modulus
takes number and divider yeah yeah
number is as high as divisor that's so
fun this is just a while loop and it
goes through and it it has a limit it
has a counter or fizzes three buzzes
fives and it will it will shout things
anyway boring but the but you can
there's idiomatic poetic literals and
idiomatic rock star who's gonna say this
I thought you were not gonna sing it
there's no the melody do you want me to
no good because I I sang last midnight
takes your heart in your soul while your
heart is as high as your soul put your
heart without your soul into your heart
give back your heart desire is a
love-struck Ladykiller my world is
nothing fire is ice hate is water until
my world is desire build my world up if
midnight taking my world fire is nothing
at midnight taking my world hate is
nothing shout fizzbuzz take it to the
top
if midnight taking my world fire is
nothing shout fizz take it to the top
if midnight taking my world hate is
nothing
buzz take it to the top whisper my world
I'm waiting for the compiler to come out
for this so the great and clever thing
the little genius bit is how he did
numeric literals so like if you want a
number right you want five or three for
fizzbuzz so the great thing about this
is he's made it so you could put almost
anything in to make numbers up which
allows you much more lyrical fun so so
tommy was a love-struck Ladykiller
initializes the value to me with the
value of 100 because a is one
love-struck is 10 and Ladykiller is
tensile so that's one zero zero sweet
Lucy was a dancer initializes sweet Lucy
with the value 16 one character and
dancer has six yes and you can do floats
- so he's got my dreams were ice a life
unfulfilled waking everybody up taking
Bruce pills initializes my dreams to PI
because there's a period after ice
so we're ice three Eric yeah Isis 3 3 .
1 4 yeah so it all works so there's a
whole specification that goes over how
to how to do loops take it to the top
it's part of the loop and and you can
it has neat keywords but it's less about
the keywords and more about their
ability to use different variables and
how they do it and it's only a
specification there is no weather for it
yet there may be soon that's wrong we
the last time we looked at this was a
couple of months ago and I've scrolled
down a couple of weeks ago all right
there are now 12 implementations oh my
goodness there are JavaScript a lexer
Java there's a whole set up right now
not Alexa
ml Python transpiler Ruby transpiler you
can you can build your career on this
now syntax highlighting 4 vs code
anymore
awesome Dylan you've done a miraculous
thing and I hope it brings you great
fame and joy in your life because I love
it there was there was the reasoning
behind it and that was one of those but
why
mainly because if we make rock star a
real and completely pointless
programming language then recruiters and
hiring managers won't be able to talk
about rock star developers anymore uh
and and Dylan is also mentioning making
stickers it's a certified rockstar
developer I will buy one I'll buy ten I
it's so we talk about languages we talk
about C++ and having to know it and
having to do it idiomatic ly and then we
look at these specifications of
languages that are odd and created for
their oddness more than their utility
although the poetic nature of it I like
it would draw me to read more codes and
to puzzle it out which is not something
I necessarily want to do if you
definitely would have to puzzle it out
this is I think you can read this and
say oh that's what this does but it is
it is pretty and we don't usually have a
lot of languages that are pretty of
course we don't even have languages that
are specified a lot of times a real
specification really rust I'm looking at
you I think you're gonna get email about
that
there's no rough specification I think
there is I thought there wasn't a couple
of the new languages people say oh you
should learn that and it's and I look it
up and I'm like yeah there is no
official specification for that language
forgive me if I don't want to write
something that is not only new doesn't
run on any of my platform
doesn't have a debugger I know how to
use which is my fault not theirs I just
I yeah how do you not have a
specification I just have you found it
yet I see you googling over there though
how hard is it I mean you just type in
rust specification or maybe rust
language because you know rust is a
thing I talked to rust specification I
don't get anything about the language
until like the eighth and then I'm the
rust documentation and then there's
the-- how do we keep banging on rust
it's I don't care I know nothing about
it other than people say we should learn
it with such vehement I just kind of
walk away gives me a reason to learn
well that's the other thing is that with
these languages some people really enjoy
learning new languages and that's what
power to uh vine but I have to get
things done I don't like doing things
things are bad I got Christopher an
outdoor couch
guess what he's working on what do you
mean oh I'm working up physically on the
couch yeah that that was what I'm sure
that was what I meant what am i working
on utan mostly yeah I moved from that
sort of greenish gloves like beige
anyway sorry rust people I don't we
don't really mean it don't know anything
about your language other than and like
it quite a lot and it will only be it
will only be karmic retribution when I'm
forced to learn it when it finally takes
over yes that is true that would be
perfect
retribution but no I don't see a
specification anyway so yeah Rockstar
pretty cool pretty cool and I like joke
projects like this because not only are
they funny but they're good learning
experiences because I bet you could look
at some of those implementations and
learn a lot about parsing and lexing
languages and stuff like that and it's
always more fun to learn
about that stuff with an example if it's
amusing then sometimes I really shine it
for ya so more power to you oh there's a
subreddit yeah and the developers
developers discord group so yes you've
written some code and released it lately
on this list there's nothing else on the
list so I'm adding things yeah I after
our conversation about you've given up
on embedded completely no no now you're
a Python developer no trace or JSON
actually I've been doing a lot with JSON
which isn't even a language against the
advice of practically everyone on
Twitter people have opinions I really do
okay so I get episode I realized that I
don't often put my small projects and
get for reasons that I don't know I mean
kit not get oh I don't version control
some of my personal projects yet out of
town it's true if something is dumb and
small I'm like why bother and one of
those things that was on the why bother
list was my little tracery robot you can
put together a JSON set of rules that
follow the tracery mapping and you can
make a generative robot for Twitter
so I think we've talked about this
before but like endless screaming is one
of them that puts in a random number of
A's in ours and geez and h's yeah some I
got I put in one that is the things you
should the things to remind me to say
things to people who are going through
bad situations in their lives so that I
don't feel overwhelmed with this feeling
of I don't know what to say the little
robot just kind of sends me things and
if I like what it says and it applies to
someone I know I will sometimes just you
know go ahead and riff off for my robot
wrote and it has been using robots to
humanize
I think it's a good approach to life but
it's just I mean it's it's a JSON set of
things and it's it's a couple hundred
lines long now and it lives on quick
BOTS done cheap or cheap butts done
quick or whatever that is and so why do
I need to commit it unless I ever want
to you know not trash everything or lose
it and so I finally committed that and
then along those same lines I wanted to
I wanted to read some old blogs but
reading old blogs is kind of a pain you
I can either page back or I can't and
read them in the wrong order or I can't
start at the beginning
and go to their website and try to never
close that tab as I update so I wanted
something that would reblog things that
would take a blog an RSS feed and it
would send me one post every day or
every n hours and then I could read the
blog in order at a rate that is faster
than they published but will eventually
put me up to date and so I made that in
Python well no I made part of that in
Python I'm still working on but I also
posted that code and I used the readme
as a bit of a chance for a creative
writing project not as creative as
Rockstar programming though and so I'm
I'm playing with Python and yeah I'm
between gigs right now I have a long
slow gig starting soon but I'm gonna
need either a couple of fasts short gigs
or at least one more long slow kick to
keep me amused so if you want me to
program preferably in C or C++ which I'm
not terrible that rust I can even do
Python machine learning oh you know I do
want to mention I put together after
some frustration with myself with
machine learning
I put together a list of all the things
I've learned in the last year about
machine learning and it came out as a
really good blog post I'm very proud of
it so if you are interested in machine
learning or have been working on it or
want to know more about it check out the
blog it's I think it's 17 machine
learning tools yeah there's a good post
so that's that's what I'm working on
no it's my chair squeaking not the
headphones sorry
side cupcakes you wouldn't I don't have
a chair squeak remover I have a lot of
stuff audio tools but chairs quick River
they haven't come in yet
that's sad so I thought maybe we should
just stop now wasn't there something
else no I mean it's 2:56 stop the
podcast yeah stand it end it well I mean
you'd be kind of disappointing to other
people I've scheduled through October
but we could just call it a different
podcast after that and start over I'd be
kind of fun I'd be kind of fun did not
have any listeners again my brain works
okay it just is so if you're the still
listening please I'm subscribed so that
at least I can feel a sense of fun that
we had back in May of 2013 when we had
20 people downloading our first episode
and we were really excited I had to go
out by myself yesterday I had to
interact with strangers who literally
demanded eye contact and chitchat it was
horrifying when did you do that I mean I
got the kitty litter
alright let's um let's close this up
thank you to Christopher for whatever
lack of cupcakes go get some cupcakes
stop squeak in your chair and grieve the
maybe the poo I'm sorry we don't record
in the mornings yes
thank you for listening thank you for
continuing listing it has been a pretty
fun ride with the last 256 episodes
except this one
we don't well there are a couple
exceptions
we don't plan on stopping soon so that
was all not real and we do like hearing
from you except about rest rest need to
find a new a new target of our ire we
can go back to pick nobody cares about
pick if you would like to contact us hit
the contact link at embedded fm you
would like to not contact us hit the
about link on it there will be show
notes that will take you to the Calvary
I am Calvary oath for medical devices
that make seen homebrew IOT projects and
of course the rock star programming
languages alright
and now Winnie the Pooh you might
remember last time when he was holding a
balloon and singing hoping the bees
would think he was a cloud the bees were
still buzzing a
suspiciously as ever some of them indeed
left their nest and flew all around the
cloud as it began the second verse of
this song one be sat down on the nose of
the cloud for a moment and then got up
again
Christopher Robin called out the cloud
yes I've been thinking I have come to
the very important decision these are
the wrong sorts of bees are they quite
the wrong sort so I think they would
make the wrong sort of honey shouldn't
you would they yes so I think I shall
come down how asked you Winnie the Pooh
hadn't thought about this if you let go
over the string he would fall bump and
he didn't like the idea of that so he
thought for a long time and then he said
Christopher Robin you must shoot the
balloon with your gun have you got your
gun of course I have you said but if I
did that it would spoil the balloon you
said but if you don't said Pooh I shall
have to let go and that would spoil me
when you put it like that you saw how it
was and you aimed very carefully at the
balloon and fired Oh Oh said Pooh did I
miss you asked you didn't exactly miss
said Pooh but you missed the balloon I'm
so sorry you said and you fired again
and this time you hit the balloon and
the air came slowly out and Winnie the
Pooh floated down to the ground but his
arms were so stiff from holding onto the
string of the balloon all that time that
they stayed up straight in the air for
more than a week and whenever a fly came
and settled on his nose he had to blow
it off and I think but I'm not sure that
this is why he's always been called to
embeded is an independently produced
radio show that focuses on the many
aspects of engineering it is a
production of logical elegance and
embedded software consulting company in
California if there are advertisements
in the show we did not put them there
and do not receive money from them at
this time our sponsors are logical
elegance and listeners like you